# **Zeming Chen**

5500 Wabash Ave, Terre Haute, IN 47892

(318) 560-4573, chenz16@rose-hulman.edu

## **Objective**

I plan to attend graduate school after graduation and pursue a Ph.D. degree in the field of natural language understanding and reasoning. My research interests are natural language processing and understanding, particularly in building models capable of human-level inference and understanding of language. My research primarily focuses on natural logic & monotonicity, neural language models, computational semantics, and natural language inference. I'm currently working on probing implicit knowledge from language models for building better semantic representations from language, and on developing a novel learning framework that train models to learn human-level reasoning process through meta reinforcement learning.

#### Education

## Rose Hulman Institute of Technology

**Bachelor of Science** 

Computer Science, Mathematics

**GPA: 3.83, 3.50** Graduate Date: May 2022

Relevant Class: Seminar on Inference, Natural Language Processing, and Artificial Intelligence

#### **PUBLICATION**

## NeuralLog: Natural Language Inference with Joint Neural and Logical Reasoning

Zeming Chen, Qiyue Gao, Lawrence S. Moss

Proceedings of the 10th Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics (\*SEM2021), Association of Computational Linguistics

https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.14167

## • Monotonicity Marking from Universal Dependency Trees

Zeming Chen, Qiyue Gao

Proceedings of the 14th International Conference on Computational Semantics (IWCS2021), Association of Computational Linguistics

https://arxiv.org/abs/2104.08659

#### • Attentive Tree Network for Monotonicity Reasoning

Zeming Chen

Proceedings of the 1sr workshop on Natural Logic meets Machine Learning (NALOMA'20), Association of Computational Linguistics.

https://arxiv.org/abs/2101.00540

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### • Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, Indiana

Research Experience Feb 2021 - April 2020

- Developed NeuralLog, an inference engine for natural language inference by joint neural and logical reasoning and dependency graph alignment
- Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, Indiana

Research Experience Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- Developed Udeo2Mono, an automatic polarity marking system using Universal Dependency for monotonicity reasoning
- Sunshine Import Export Inc, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China

ERP Software Developer June 2019 - Sep 2019

- Developed and deployed an enterprise resources planning system.
- Java web application built with Spring Boot and MySQL database.

#### **SKILLS**

- **Programming:** Proficient in Python, JavaScript, Java, C/C++, scheme,
- Deep Learning: implemented and applied convolution neural networks (ResNet, EfficientNet, FPN),

recurrent neural network(LSTM, GRU), graph neural network (Tree-LSTM, graph-Conv). Had experience with Pytorch, TensorFlow, and Keras. Finetuned roBERTa and BERT.

• **Machine Learning:** implemented and applied SVM, logistic regression, principal component analysis, naive Bayesian, decision tree, and random forest.

### **PROJECTS**

• Automatic Social Distance Monitoring (Summer 2020)

Real-time pedestrian detection and social distance analyzing. A C++ project built with OpenCV. YOLOv3 is used to detect and localize pedestrians. Euclidean distance is used to calculate the distance between each person.

• Knowledge Graph Enhanced Dialog System (Spring 2019)

Research Project on improving dialog system performance by incorporating knowledge graphs through a graph attention mechanism.

#### Certificate

• C++ Nanodegree (Summer 2020)

From Udacity

• Deep Learning Specialization Certificate (winter 2019)

From Deeplearning.ai

• Quantum Machine Learning (spring 2019)

From EPFLx

• Computational Neuroscience: Neuronal Dynamic of Cognition

From EPFLx